Robin Choi

<u>robinchoii@gmail.com</u> | 206-696-0799 | Seattle, WA linkedin.com/in/robinchoii | github.com/robinchoii | robinchoii.github.io

SUMMARY

I am a Full stack developer who specializes in Ruby on Rails and knowledgeable in JavaScript frameworks to transform ideas into user friendly websites. My competitive nature in sports taught me to be a team player which translates to working in agile development and git workflow.

SKILLS

- Web Design Ruby, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript (jQuery), AJAX
- Database Systems MySQL, PostgreSQL, ActiveRecord
- Git Workflow in Agile Development (Kanban Project Management)
- Test Driven Development with RSpec, Capybara and Jasmine
- MVC Frameworks built applications with Ruby on Rails and Sinatra
- Object Oriented Programming

PROJECTS

Golf Skins

Web application and mobile friendly. Quick and easy way to keep track of friendly golf wagers with your friends! Enter all the skins, pars, birdies, and more into the fields and it will calculate who owes who in real time. No more staring at the scorecard trying to do all the math in you head! Built with Angular, HTML5, CSS3, and Bootstrap.

<u>HolidaySurvivor.Ninja</u> – Hack the Dot Seattle (1st place)

Two-hour hackathon to build a funny functional website based off the domain name HolidaySurvivor.ninja. The website features like clicking a button to randomize and display a funny holiday tip along with a picture. You can add a tip with a URL to the picture associated with it. Built with HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery.

Shop n Stop

Shop n Go is an e-commerce website I created for buying products using the Stripe API. I have implemented Elasticsearch to help you find your items as well a category section to help narrow down your search. Primarily built with node.js, HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery connected to monogoDB database.

<u>PickUp</u>

A web application to connect people by playing sports. From one on one to groups activities, PickUp finds events nearby based off your location using the Google Maps API. Primarily built using Ruby on Rails and Javascript with PostgreSQL on the backend. jQuery and AJAX to make the site dynamic and interactive.

Flapper News

Flapper News is a single page application to post interesting articles we find around the internet. This was a quick project my friend Wei and I worked on for the purpose of learning AngularJs and the basic fundamentals to build powerful front-end applications. We learned more about directives, two-way data binding, controllers and much more.

EXPERIENCE

Latchel
Front End Engineer Contractor

Seattle, WA

Dec 2016 - Jan 2017

- Rebuilt a pricing calculator based off the number of units managed and price per unit
- Eliminated a monthly expense from a 3rd party calculator by building an in-house calculator

Stone Korean Restaurant Manger/Server

Redmond, WA Dec 2011 – Jun 2015

- Increased sales by 30% by restructuring item prices based off popularity
- Partnered with a delivery service company to increase lunch sales by 40%

EDUCATION

Dev Bootcamp

San Francisco, CA Jul 2015 – Nov 2015

Full Stack Web Development

- 1000+ hours in an intensive 19-week curriculum focused on building web applications with JavaScript, Ruby on Rails, jQuery, SQL, HTML and CSS
- Collaborated daily by pair-programming to help each other understand concepts
- · Maximized productivity in teams with agile methodologies
- Implemented giving and receiving actionable, specific, and kind 360-degree feedback to improve weaknesses and pad our strengths